graph the lines yal X and Y = RX + a
where R and A are positive real numbers
with r less than 1 these intersect at
the point where the X and the y
coordinate are both a over 1 - R the
vertical distance on the y- AIS between
the two curves is a and that means this
horizontal distance is also a because it
forms an isoceles triangle using the
line yal X as we continue to step up the
staircase diagram we can measure the
vertical distance as the difference
between two curves and the horizontal
distance will always be the same as that
one because it again forms an isoc
triangle with yal x the vertical and
horizontal lengths in the staircase
diagram are all of the form a * R to the
I as I increases and this means that the
widths decrease as the staircase
converges to the intersection point if
we focus only on the horizontal line
segments and start dropping them to the
x-axis we see that a plus a r plus a r 2
plus a R cubed and so on eventually
creates the entire line segment on the
x- axis from 0 to a over 1 - R therefore
the infinite sum of the geometric series
with first term a and common ratio R
must equal a over 1 - r